<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Saadat Qadri</title><link href="http://saadatqadri.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://saadatqadri.com/feeds/python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://saadatqadri.com/</id><updated>2014-05-22T10:20:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Getting started with GitHub Pages and Pelican</title><link href="http://saadatqadri.com/github-pages-pelican-blogging.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-22T10:20:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Saadat Qadri</name></author><id>tag:saadatqadri.com,2014-05-22:github-pages-pelican-blogging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started writing a blog earlier this year, with the intention of capturing my ideas and &lt;em&gt;fleeting&lt;/em&gt; thoughts. I initially started a Tumblr blog, wasn't too happy with the themes available for free, and then switched over to &lt;a href="svbtle.com"&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt;, a new, minimalist writing platform by Dustin Curtis. I was really excited about the minimalist feel of Svbtle at first, and some of the people I'm following (Nima Gardideh (Frank &amp;amp; Oak)) maintained a Svbtle blog. However, the lack of certain features - adding Disqus comments, and the ability to modify the base Svbtle theme was a bit limiting. I wanted people to comment on my articles. I wanted to elicit discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short - I moved my content from Svbtle to Medium, and I started looking at options for hosting a "landing page" for myself. I played around with Ghost and Wordpress, but I just wanted a simple way to get my content online. After a bit of research, GitHub Pages was what I was looking for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed directions on these three articles to get my Pelican blog running on GitHub pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://martinbrochhaus.com/pelican2.html"&gt;Pelican and GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://terriyu.info/blog/posts/2013/07/pelican-setup/"&gt;How I Set Up Pelican&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages"&gt;GitHub Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** More details soon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="publishing"></category></entry></feed>